When we were planning this
retreat, Tim and I were
thinking about what classes
to teach.  It is not bad luck in
Buddhism not to finish the teaching.
As the last lamri, we taught for 12
years, we finished it, and we should
applaud ourselves.
[music]
There is another very important
teaching which
is called, say,
danjin
means, and our habit of thinking that the
pen comes from the pen, of clinging to the
pen, yes, and thinking that it comes from
itself and not from
When you hold on, when you believe that
the pen was made in a factory, you have a
mental field which is called
danjin.  And everyone has this disease.
Even when you train your hands, everyone has
this disease.  This is funny.  This is a
very, very old disease.  Shandei
means quarrels between two people.
Por.  We have something special if you
come see it.  This
is called a fight or a dispute on the road.
This is when two drivers start
arguing on the road and when they stop the
car and jump out at each other, they
start arguing and cursing.
And our friend ran into someone on the road
in Rimrock, and he ran out of the car, started
yelling at this guy, and he
showed him the finger.  And he said, "Okay,
okay, good, I've calmed down."  And this is this, this is this
, when we
meet someone, this is called Tibet
Tibetan shandem.
This is a fight, a quarrel, an argument.  And in this
book it's a long book of poetry
called "Pain with the good
side of your mind and with the bad side of your
mind."  It is such a bitter fate, a struggle.
The teacher introduced these teachings to me
many years ago, probably
35 or 40 years
ago.  And he gave us this very
long teaching, and he could not finish
it.  He died before completing these
teachings.  And it is, by the way, bad luck not
to finish these exercises.  And I thought that I would like to
teach you this today and
finish these teachings.  And then I would
feel that we had completed these
exercises.  This is an incredible book.
Incredible book.  It's a struggle in your
mind.  This mind of yours is divided into two
parts.  Good side, bad side.
Angel and demon.  And they fight.  They are fighting.
And it's an incredible conversation.  Incredible.
And that conversation in our head that
happens with time in our
mind.  Yes, this guy really
hurt me.  No, do you remember the pen?  Yes, I
know this pen, but this other guy
gave me a hard time.  We all say this
every day to ourselves, in our minds.  Yes,
thousands of times a day.  I do it.  I'm sitting in
my
house, I'm cold.
What's the coolest thing you
could do for a
llama?  Put them in the shrine, because
all the toilets there
are heated, everyone is
warm.  I feel like I'm going to pee
when I sit in this toilet, which is
warm, and when I come to Diamond
Mountain and go to the toilet outside, it's so
cold, I don't even want to sit down.  But I
sit down and I'm like, "Wow, what a nasty
cold, cold pot."  Even
then I argue my mind.  My mind argues with its own
mind.  This is a very, very beautiful
book.  What year did we start,
Tim?  We started 14 years
ago.  I won't have much time
to teach this, but I refuse to
refuse to teach you this.
And if you are a student of the
secret of the secret path, if you are a person of the
diamond path, maybe I
have sent this book to you
now.
Maybe you could say,
"Yes, of course," or "No."  It is
possible that your path, the diamond
path, connects with this book.
Maybe this book should help you on your
diamond path.  This is how I look at
it.  I'm not
finished.  It will take approximately 3-4
years to complete these exercises.  And I
want to finish these teachings.  And it has never
been branched out before.
I would like
these teachings to be available to people around the world.  And for me,
when I teach, I understand better myself.
By teaching and explaining, I
understand better myself.  You tova, you all teachers, when
you want to teach well, when you
know, try it on your sister, on
your son.  How old is he?  19. Wow.
He will be a DC teacher next
year.  I went to talk to someone in the
audience.  I think Guda sent you this
book and you should finish it
with
me.  And I include this in our Diamond
Way course.  But basically this is an argument and the
meaning of emptiness.  This is a unique book
because it is
funny.  It was written in such a
way to be
funny.
Sometimes laugh, even if you just don't
understand, say:
"Ha-ha-ha".  Yes, it's funny.
But this is the
truth, this is
self-criticism, this is what I do before
I sit down here to
teach, this is who I
blame.  Well, let's do it
here,
right?  They do this on a warm morning.
But why?  Why is it so cold?
later in the day doesn't make sense, you know?   Do
you understand?  Have you seen what I complain about,
criticize?  You are always complaining about
something or someone in your mind.   Yes.
And here, in this case, it is the devil
who speaks and who complains.  Tim
and I worked on this text
because you heard about the five houses idea.  And what's
going on with ACI?
what
I
think is one of the oldest
organizations that we have in
existence.  I think we organized it
in 1993, 32 years
ago.  This organization grew and
grew, becoming larger.
started, then DCI
started and
other SSDs and PBB, he's joking.
Other organizations
started almost 40 years ago and it became a
very large organization.
If you, that is, take, go through 18
courses, thorough
courses, basically it will take you 6
or 7 years.  And if you continue with
diamond courses, it’s 6 or 7 years, which
makes 14 years.  Then you have to
work on your meditation.  This is another 5
years, which makes a total of 19
years.  Then you have to train someone.
That is, you must do all this
before you die.  It's too much,
you know?  Too much of everything.  And what did we
think?  What's happening?  We would like
you all to become
teachers.  We really want
you all to teach.  If you are so
stubborn that you come to the desert and
attend these desert teachings,
most likely you will be taught to
be a teacher.  It's very much like
being in a diamond mountain because
there are a lot of
[music]
problems.  And we thought that the people who
come to these teachings would especially
teach the Diamond Way.  And these will be
incredible teachers.  This is my dream.  And so that
you become a teaching?  There are so many things to
learn.
You can't study soroped and then
become a teacher because you won't have any
hair left.  You
see, my idea is that you might
specialize in something.  It's like you're
going to
university.  You don’t
get, for example, a diploma in
English or science or something else.
at Columbia University or other
universities.  Our idea is
that you will choose a
specialization and we
invite you to all classes, but
maybe you can look inside your
heart.  And you have five
features, five choices.  You can
do your PhD and then
teach in one of these
houses.  Yes, it’s like that at universities.   In
Pristan you must join
some house and you are very loyal to that
house.  And you have friends, and you have
support, you study together, and you
graduate together in your home.  And we
wanted to make five houses here as well.  And
what is your first choice?  By the way, the
first rule of a teacher.  If you don't
remember something, ask the audience.  Do you
remember the first
house?  You can choose the traditional
classic
house
path.  18 + 18 36 courses.  You can
basically do this with Geshi, so if you
have completed the 18 main
courses, you have completed the main important
topics of the
Geshi course.  By the way, they don't sit for 12 hours
every day.  They take breaks all the time
.  They, um, don't even know when the
next lesson is.
You go to class and they tell you: "Oh, there
was no class today."  And we say:
"We didn't know."  They don't talk, they don't
study, like we study in universities.
This is a very crazy
system.
You
will end up with philosophy, some
philosophy, some
people, some people study philosophy very much and
love to study philosophy.  Yes, I am the same.
I love talking about philosophy.  This is exactly how I
learned things.
Yes, if I wanted to come to the path of income,
and then I would become a Buddha, then
I would choose this path of the philosopher.  Then
this is the house of Samati, this is meditation.  We will
say: "Study this book."  Here, this is the
book.  The last 35 books
weren't enough.
Then you will ask, can I
meditate?  I don't want to read books
all day.  And many people prefer,
some people prefer meditation, and
they really enjoy
it.  And their dream is to be a
meditation teacher, not a Tibetan teacher.  And that's
great.  And we should have, and yes, we
should have, a house that is dedicated to
special meditation.  It is a privilege and a
pleasure to join the house of
Samatiya, the house of
meditation.  You'll probably look
like, By the way, great meditators,
really great meditators, as we
call them, they don't kind of
glow.  Brady is probably one of the
best meditators I know.  It
doesn't show itself, it doesn't shine.  It doesn't
look like this, as you see on
this
slide.  Here.  Do you see?  Yes.
I mean, what do I mean
?  It's so
simple.  You may look like a
businesswoman, as if you are involved in
import, export, or head of some kind of
corporate organization
.   For
those who don't know, it all depends on
you.  If you are really attracted to
meditation, you have this interest, and
when you see your future, you
close your eyes and see that you are
teaching meditation to a group of
people, how to meditate, then we
invite you to this house.  This doesn't mean
you can't listen to philosophy.  This
means that you
specialize when I when I
decide what I am, what
choice.  This is what I tell people on the
plane.  You sit next to someone on an
airplane.  You don’t even know, you
ask what you are doing, what you are
doing.
And if you are a person who
will say, who will say: "I am a
meditation teacher," then you should come to
this house, join your house.  If
you are studying philosophy, then you should
join an
ACI house.  Classic house, huh?  What do we
call it?  So, the third
house.  What do we
call the
house?
Nagare.  Yes, indeed, I really
enjoy going on retreats.  And there are
people, they always lack them.  They
want to do retreats all the time
.  Tell me, I read this
book, I would like to teach you wholesale.
Sorry, I'm busy.  I'm sitting in my chalet.
And I don’t know, I can’t read a book.
The only thing they want is to
be somewhere in the mountain, on the
mountain themselves, in deep
retreat, maybe meeting with people
once every 6
years.  May be.
So, if you are the kind of
person who
dreams, who constantly spends
a lot of time in
retreats, then you can join
this
house.  I'm not
sure what percentage of
people will choose.
I don't know which of these houses will be
more popular, but I believe
that if at least five people are in
each house to start with, that's enough.
I don't care how much it will be.  I don't care
how much.  100
people in a classic house or two
people in a retreat house.  It doesn't matter.
I want you to take where you want to
be.  And what is the fourth?   Yes.
Lamrim.  House of
Ramrimam.  As you have seen over the last 12 years,
Lamrim is a big topic.  We call it the
big one theme.
Lamrim.
John.  Dan
John's Base.  Several hundred lamrims.  You
can devote your whole life to studying
lamrims.
And a lot of
beautiful ones.  The one we finished 12
years ago.  Lamrinchomo,
yes, we taught this for 12 years.  And you can
become a
lamrim master.  And maybe this is it, it is very
sweet and very wonderful, beautiful.
This may be what you want.  And,
of course, everyone wants to be in the fifth
house.  Diamond House.
Because everyone wants to be in this house.  I won't
lie to you.
No, I don't allow this to happen
because you will be ignoring all the other
four houses.  And our
plan is to join one of the four
houses.  You don't decide this today
.  It doesn't mean you have to
sign the contract today.  Just
think about which one attracts you the most
.  I'll tell you, it's very
deep.  My teacher gave
me my teacher's advice on all five topics of Gesha.  He
said, "There is one that you
hate, topics that you
hate."  And he asked: "Which one is it?
Thirteenth
year. Why is this an unlucky, unlucky
number? I hate
logic. Then you will become a
master."
His advice was: join a house
you don't
like because that's what you're not
very good at.  And when you balance
your life, when you become a master of what
you are not interested in, then
you become a master of everything.  You see,
you balance this, you learn to do
retreats and study philosophy.  That is, there is
such an option too.  I'm not
pushing you there.  If you have always
thought and dreamed of sitting in your own
little cottage or chalet in the mountains, you
can join this
house.  Choose what you want.  You are
free to make your
choice.  But what we are asking is a
week of you.
As if imagine that in one of these,
feel how it feels
inside you.  Yes, I said it, I told my
life, but you will never repeat it to
your
wife.
Yes, I took her to the store to
buy
jeans.  The one in the store that doesn't have
special seats for husbands.  You have to
stand and wait while she tries on all
those jeans.
Yes, she used 42 pairs of jeans.
How many of them did she buy?  Zero pairs.  She didn't
buy a single pair of jeans.  What does this
mean?  I say, "Try different
houses, feel how it is for you. We are
not pushing you, we are not forcing you
to choose today.
Try, what is the most
cool thing that
I did on my tour, on the last
tour that I did it. Tanley
knows. I was very brave and bought her
jeans. And they fit.
Imagine, after I die and
write my life story, it should
begin with him buying his
wife
jeans. So these houses are like in Harry
Potter in the movie Harry
Potter. How did they decide which house
they
belonged to, how did they decide that. He
asks the audience.
What is it
called? Oh, yeah, there was such a hat.
We didn't have that hat. We didn't choose
that hat. Harry Potter. So you
put on this hat, and this hat talked to you
. We didn't have that
hat. We don't have that hat, so you
have to decide for yourself.
Which house will we choose for Harry Potter?
So now this
week's game. You buy when  Tim
will tell you, you must choose the volume in which
you would like to be.
This means what you would like to
teach, what you would like to teach
people. And you will focus on
this. And we will
help you focus, and we will help you
become a
specialist, a doctor in this field. And
we will specially create courses for you. And
this does not mean that other people
cannot come.
We will specially create courses so that you
become the youngest, the coolest
teacher in this house. And then,
if you have to fulfill
certain requirements, then you can
join the diamond
house. That is, your house, one of the four,
is your road to come to the diamond
house.
Therefore, we ask you to choose
one of these houses that will lead you
to the diamond house. It is such a
system. This will be a super house for those who
were cool in their house.
Think about what you would like
to teach. Visualize,
imagine that you are a teacher. What is the
most
important diamond
teaching? You can imagine it when
you are
budan. This is one of the most  important. That
is, you can imagine how you
do the meditation when you are. What would
you teach
people? When John and I are, we will have
lots and lots of hair, a cap of
hair. And my tummy will go away.
One of the Diamond Path exercises is
to visualize
yourself as who you want to become. And sometimes
you will do. And now we will
talk about this. And
now
we have a book
called The Angel Devil Debate.
We will do Flow
Dark. This is the file I use. I
take
the book like we had in the last
lesson. The book that
Gibson translated. It is on my
computer. Yes, I open it and I insert
a photo there. And I
teach from this photo, just like I
did in the last lesson.
But I don’t have a picture of the Angel Devil Debate
. Why? Because you will make
this picture in each
house. Each house
will make a picture that will
teach this part of this
book. I will teach you
today one of some
poems about an angel and a devil.
It happens
that a bad
friend was very
disrespectful to a good
friend. And I would like each of the
houses to lead you in this. You will
sit together and
draw these
idems, these pictures, on how to teach
this. And then we will have special
classes, which will be divided into four
parts. Each house will rise and say:
"Here is our picture for the first verse."
This is how we would teach the first
verse from our house." From our house,
the best house. Right? So
you have to be very loyal to your
house. You need to have Harry
Potter expertise.
It even reads books when it walks.
Yeah, but here you can't
because we have snakes here. So be
careful when you
go out.
And today, I used to have a
contract with
an agency, a photo agency, and I bought
photos from them. I did this for several years
, paid them for photos.
Instead of searching for it on
the Internet, I had a contract, and I
bought photos from
them. And now
we have artificial intelligence,
which is getting better and better.
Now you can make these photos
with artificial intelligence. It's
called pram. And you write a phrase,
for example, and a woman throws spaghetti
on her head. A friend who is meditating,
and it makes
a picture for you. Sometimes they even make
a picture of a person who has five
fingers. He jokes, because
artificial intelligence does not  Always does
hands. I really
like it. And most likely in your
future
there is a video of you with artificial
intelligence. I think artificial
intelligence is cool. I mean, you
can use artificial
intelligence, you can create an image.
And it's a cool
tool. And the audience is interested.
It entertains and artificial intelligence
entertains the speakers. And
then it's a great tool
to ask your students, what is
this picture about? And what does this
picture mean? The picture has to have
power. It has to be a strong story,
that is, such a strong picture that
will tell a story.
It's much easier to remember philosophies from a
picture. So, we will tell stories with
pictures. I don't choose these pictures. I
want four pictures for each of the house of
minds. And I want to see what your house
does. Then Tim and I will decide which
one is
best. We will give you a golden hat.
No, that's too American.
American. Well, well, in the meantime, we
will just
enjoy ourselves. There was a very famous
guy from
Mexico who has a new
show.  Oh no, he has a show.
Show news. We had a contest. Yes. Come
here we are. Yes. How much? 10 years ago. Yes.
And he did, by the way, the best one. He
won a
prize. And it was incredible. Zhala
is talking about
Juan, the peach dere show that he
hosts. By the way, he just returned from
Kyoto. We should applaud
him. He and Adam, they gave a teaching in
Kyoto.
They taught an interesting course in
Kyoto. Thanks to our Japanese friends
who helped them
there. Juan and Adam Andrade taught
interesting classes, and they received a grant
from
Tim to fly to Kyoto and
teach.
Yes,
by chance.
And the plane stopped in
Hawaii, and Juan went, went to
Hahu. That's a place called
Hawaii. It's in the north of Hawaii. And where Shla
says that he lived and
surfed there. Which of these two beaches do you
go to and say: "Do this?"
on or the northern northern beach. That is,
there are two
beaches in Huaku  and the northern
beach. There are a lot of beautiful women in
bikinis there.
That's right, I don't know which beach you
were on.
Well, if you want to try something in
this sense, you can
apply, get a
grant. And they flew to Kirota, and they
helped a lot of
people and sold a cool course.
And anyone can do it. It's
called Jeep Box.
Jeep Box. I'll talk about it. So,
today I'm going to teach the debate between an angel and a
devil. Then I'll explain to you.
Think of the picture you
want to create of your home. This
will help you
teach. And also pictures keep people, and
they don't help them stay
awake, right? They help people
remind themselves of things. And in my understanding, in
my view, that everyone today
in this class or online, you must,
you can
learn, and you can become a good
teacher. It's your responsibility.
Each of you is
different. Adam is not here. I'll tell you about
his first class. Can I show you?
It was about 12 years ago. It was
in
Phoenix. I was training him to
speak, stood up, and he said
this. He just froze on
stage. I said, "Adam." And he
stood like this:
"Adam, Adam, sit down." He did. Okay,
we'll work on this. He completely
froze. I froze too, the first time
I went on stage, my teacher sat down,
told me, "Sit down and shut up." So,
you will learn this. You will learn in my
understanding, in my
opinion. Everyone who listens to
this class today can be a teacher and
should be a teacher. And in
the tradition of the ancient books, you cannot
take a
class, be in a class, if you do
not have the intention of becoming a teacher. Right?
This is our old tradition. You cannot be
present in a class unless you have
the intention of teaching and passing on
these teachings.
Sometimes I would ask, "Are you
listening?" If you have ordinary
delicious food, then I will listen to you.
So, let's begin.
The devil is talking,  the bad part
of yours. And he says that you have to lead
people to
something when you're not thinking about anything.
That is, your concentration should be
melted, when you're
not
thinking about anything.
Sit down, relax, don't think about anything.
Just talk to yourself. Oh, who's talking about this
? Who's
talking now? It's the devil. You
understand, this is my meditation, my
system. You're laughing, right? A long time ago
, when I met my
first yoga teacher, I said:
"Listen, I don't know if I can, I don't know if I
can do yoga or not.  I do
n't know if I can do this in yoga.  I
travel a lot."
And they
said, "We have a tip, when you
arrive, when you get to the hotel,
wherever you go, whatever country
you go to, find a yoga studio." There's a
great story.
And in Chinese, I went to China,
and there was a class
for pregnant women, but I didn't understand
what she was saying. I went to this
class, and everyone there was pregnant
. It was the most amazing
stretch I ever got in that
class.
So, I would like to
tell you, because I've traveled to
all these countries, I've gone to these yoga studios. I
mean, every time I
traveled, I went to a new
yoga studio. And I've
heard
1,100 terrible meditations,
meditation classes.
And think of nothing.
Relax, let go of your thoughts. And I'm
like,
[music]
"Okay." Then suddenly,
I thought, how much bad
meditation
is taught to people. I was
shocked. You know, there are
very few people who
They teach meditation correctly. And this has been going on for
400 years. And this teacher,
this Loshki Henson, this
writer, this is the man who
stopped the war from his retreat. And he
even said that even 400 years
ago, people taught meditation
incorrectly by saying, "Think about nothing."
And in this book, it's the devil.
And this is a very important thing, when you
put this
picture together, this is not a very bad
yoga class. By the way,
sometimes the asanas are very good, the yoga is good,
the meditation before the asana is not very good,
but very often these yoga teachers are
wonderful. And that's why I still
continue to go to these yoga classes.
They give you these
headphones when they start teaching
meditation and leave them for their own ears, so as
not to listen to what they are teaching us.
But when they do yoga, I listen and
follow their
instructions. Yes, this is an old
problem when they think that
meditation is thinking about nothing. So,
listen. In the tantric sense, the
diamond
path. The goal  the diamond
path to achieve the goal before you
die. And you don't
think about
it. Who will die first, who will die
last, we don't know. But don't
think, it's usually random.
I hear the feeling that there is no one
left. We don't know who will be
next, who will die next. And we don't
know who will be first and who will be
last. And this is the reality in this
diamond path system you
are trying to achieve the goal before you
die. And it's a run, it's a
marathon, yes, it's a race.
And you and someone will say: "Remember that
woman?" Yeah, she's gone. She
had a car accident, so it's a
race. And everyone is sorry for about three minutes,
and then they ask: "What's for lunch?"
Yes, we are all in the diamond path race.
Yeah, see, I'm inserting pieces of the
diamond path into each of you, what I say
is a race. This is the thought of the diamond
path, the reason for the diamond path, the most
important idea to achieve this. And then
relax,  Relax, yes, if you're not
dying, and if you're not dying yet,
that's okay. I know, I know what's going to
happen to me when I die, where I'll
end up. The teachers are waiting for me.
Yes, I have it all lined up. And you
have to do it, and you have to take care
of it when you can. You have to
take care of it now. And this is the
diamond
path, the one-life focus. So
this person who teaches you and
tells you to meditate on nothing is
actually killing you. It's not just
a joke.
They have to go to
Samatya's house, wasting my 10 minutes. It's not 10
minutes. It's not 10 minutes before class.
It's irreplaceable time that you
lose in your life spending in this
meditation. I sold my company to Warn
Buffett. I sold it
for He had 81 bil, and now he has
143 trillion. Today he's 90, 94, I don't
know how much  him.
If he has 143 trillion, I think
he can buy a few hours from
someone. So, 100 million in
money. I don't I don't care how much it
costs. I'll take a piece of your life, but you
can't do that even if you have
that much money, no one can. So
the person who teaches you this creepy
meditation, he's killing you. They're killing and
stealing your time. The most valuable thing in
your life is a
tragedy. It's worse than if you had
Yeah, yeah, it's probably a tragedy. It's not
even comparable to the diarrhea that could
happen right now. Right? He's
laughing because Rob was having diarrhea right now
. This is not
a joke, this is not a small thing. This is not
just you wasted 10 minutes before yoga.
This meaning is that no one can
give you back this time that you
lost.
Yeah, it's probably kinder to cut your
hand open. At least you can
lock this hand and
return it to normal  state. But
this is a serious debate,
right? That's because he's killing people,
killing their hearts, not their bodies.
He's teaching them the wrong meditation.
It's a tragedy. It's like
someone being killed and dying in a
car crash.
Right.
This
devil talks about how quickly
systems work. They will achieve results from
meditation that
exist neither in this life nor in the
next life. Yes, they will achieve
results from meditation that exist neither
in this life nor in the next. And they
will achieve futures. They can
sit back, meditate together for three days
, and thanks to this, each of them
will achieve liberation. Who's talking about this
now? Who's talking now?
Listen. Give me the diamond path. The
fastest way, but it takes a long
time. If someone
promises you quick liberation, let me
tell you something, share some wisdom,
like an old man.
This is what happened to me. Someone
sat next to me on a
plane. I'd like to know a secret about this
market. You need to
invest.
invisible. They have special chips. You
need to invest in this
NDM company. And you will make money immediately.
And the founder of Sony corporation, what was his
name? What was his name? What was his What
was his name?
Mr. Murito. Okay. What he
said, it's a great book. What's the
name of this
book? Yeah, it's Made in Japan. This
book is called Made in Japan. And I
love this book. Let me
tell you something. If someone knows something, which
stock will go up or down, do you
think they'll really share it with you
? Logic. The logic is just
ironclad. If someone knows
100% that your stock will go up,
why should they
tell you? They're just investing their
money, you know?
And he
laughed. I don't gamble with these
stocks. That's what, that's what the
founder of Sony corporation said. I
don't buy stocks. Why? It's like a
casino. It's the same thing. Nobody can
say what will happen tomorrow, and what  It will be
the day after tomorrow. You can talk to
anyone. Everyone will say something
different. If they knew, they wouldn't be
experts because they would be
making a ton of money and wouldn't be doing
this. Do you understand why I'm telling you this
? This guy is promising
you
the impossible. Look,
I'm a master, I have a certain
hat. I can say, "Wow, wow." I
tell
the guy, "Look at this thing, look at
my moats."  I have this tool.
This confirms that I am a
master.  I have statues, I have I have
and all these tools.  And I
have students, I can bring you here
in 3 days.  It's like the stock market, yes,
which I just
talked about.  You can make your
day, but I need to get back to my
work, to my lesson.  Do you understand what
I'm talking about?
This hat they
wear, it will not lead you to
Budovost.
So, the promise you can't
keep is that you can come
instantly.
Yes, it will be hard work, constant
work.  You need to sit on your butt.
vm retreat and have a lot of bad
days.  That's right, JB, and a very difficult
time.  Then you will reach your
goal.  The Diamond Way is not a piece of
chocolate or
candy.  Does that mean I should
shut up,
Brian?   Yes.
I like this next verse.
This moro in English means a
very, very stupid person or a fool
in Russian.  Who is talking about this?  Yes, an
idiot who can't tie all his
shoelaces.  And he
accuses
this angel of wisdom of understanding the
pen.  And he says, "You're just an
idiot."  And he says, "Why are you
talking? She's not upset, of course
, she's an
angel. And he says, "I can do
incredible things, and you're just a nice
lady.
Yes, you are
John." In English we say: "You are
so stupid that you can't tie your
shoelaces." Here
Smith, have you never seen these words?
This is a distant usang from the 10th
century. Shi
means every
week means who you are. He accuses her of being
too good a person. Who is talking about
this? The devil. You are an idiot who can't
tie his shoelaces.
He blames the angel for not
staying. You are so beautiful, so
smart, wise. You understand the pen, you
live, understanding the pen. And
why? Why are you never
home? Where are you all
day? Who are you with, who do you spend
time with? Why do you never come
home now? So beautiful, you are so
compassionate, wise. You are never
home. What does he
mean? When he asks this, what does
he
mean? It is really to understand
the pen once a
month. He accuses her of being a bad
lady, a bad wife.
Because he must live with her in her
mind. The devil must live in a person, in the mind
person, one person next to
this beautiful woman with this
angel. And she's like, "Who is this guy?
What is his name?  Where did you go?  What are you
doing?  Why are you never here?   Do
you understand what I'm talking about?
This
means that people think about the pen
once a
week.  All week they complain about other
people.  I had no idea, I had no
idea.  He must do it.  Such a
bad
person once a
month.  And this is happening because of me.  That's what
I did.  And she is not at home very often
.   Do
you understand?  You, you should laugh.  You
must let me know that you
understand this.  Why are you silent?  I think it's
cool.  He accuses her of being
unfaithful to her
husband.  This is ignorance.  They live together,
but he doesn't
see her.  She's never home because
it's so cool.  Geshila makes
a metaphor that we remember about the pen
very rarely, that's the whole point, right?  That
means you have to make a nice picture
for this.  Got it?  For this, for this
verse.  Do you understand?
How much time do we have left?
A few minutes.  Very
good.  Let's do
the following.  There is an error in the
spelling here.
Those who hope to create good
[music]
karma, who talks about this?
We can
call it 2 minutes of
Buddha.  I don't understand why the whole world doesn't
fall at my feet.  If they do my
meditation, they will come to Buddhahood
in a few days.
Yes, if you really want to
get a good kamu,
by the way, they are trying to trick you into
misfiling your taxes.  But in
Buddhism, but in Buddhism he asks, the devil
asks to believe that the handle comes from
its own side.
But if he makes you believe that the
pen does not happen on its own, that
is, if the pen happens on its
own, then he is
successful.  And if he succeeded in
doing this, then you became his
slave.  That
means you
will blame people all your
life.
You should
envy me because I am so
strong and you are so weak.  Who's
speaking?  Devil.  Yes, the devil.  This is
true.  It's not that
she's weak.  Every time she is at home,
she beats him up good and hard.  But if you
think about it, you will be patient with
other people.  But if you don't remember,
you're weak, right
?  She is
stronger, but
if she is never at home here in
our minds, she has no opportunity
to show her strength.  Do you understand what
I'm talking about?  Yes.  You need to learn
this Yashi Michael old way.  When you
fall asleep, you talk, you show like this
, you shake your head, right?
OK.  This is the third level of our
skills.  Ah, and the next level is sleeping with your
eyes open.  Just sit up straight and don't
fall over.  Stand with your
eyes open.  Now you are so tired.
Now you're so tired of arguing with me all the
time.  Why don't you
come home?  It's so hard for you to
come.
Why?  Just don't come home.
Forget about it.  Where does this
person come from?  We have already decided that the person
who brought me pain, he happens on his own
.  This is a bad person.  And then
we don’t need to remember and memorize
Buddhism.  It's such a struggle.   to
be a Scythrenic.  What is a
skefrenik?  You hurt me.  You
told me something.  Oh, wait.  He
comes from me.  It can't happen to
me.  No,
no, no.  It would be easier if you just
forgot about all your Buddhism.  Something
happened to you Bol and said:
"Idiot, meet my mother."  Come on.
Yes, stupid fool.  It would be easier for me
than all this struggle of Buddhism in my
head.  Maybe this is because of me
.  No, maybe some
people, but not this one.
Yeah, he's like, "Why don't you just
come home and leave this house?"  These are his
last
words.  Now a beautiful woman.  This
angel appears again.
Woman of wisdom.  She comes home
and says, "Hi, honey, I'm home."
She understands the pen and she uses
her
lives.  Some people understand the pen but
never use it in their life, right?  And
some use this for their own
understanding.   A
joker without a
friend.  We have 1 minute left.
Hold on, hold on, don't fall asleep.
When I was sitting in
Gesha’s course, and in the camp for
rabid people, when it was 45°C
hot, and
the rain, the rain poured down on me
completely.  Yes.
I made a promise.  I
promised that in the future, when I am a teacher, I will make
them
suffer.  Now it has become my dream.
You see, I am living my
dream.  I really had this
dream.  This was This was a thought in
my mind.  And
you? You are ignorant.  You don't have a
single good quality, and you
have the illusion that you are a good
meditation master.  Not only you.  You don't have
any remarkable qualities.  You don't
even have the tools to create these
qualities.  It means that in this case you don’t
know how to meditate.  Nobody
ever taught you how to meditate.  You
think that thinking about nothing is
meditation and therefore you will never
become good.
human, because you don't have
the skills, you don't have the tools.
This is what we call meditation,
because you think meditation is
sitting and thinking about nothing.  So,
great.